

# **AVINASH DHUMAL**

ASSOCIATE MANAGER - IT

## CONTACT INFO



+91-779-840-6759



avinash\_dhumal@yahoo.com



LinkedIn Profile



Online Profile



Hacker Rank Profile



Pune, MH, India

#### **ABOUT ME**

11.5+ years of software architect, design, development, management, and support experience using Azure & AWS Cloud infrastructures. I have developed, managed, and led client, database, and enterprise applications/products on Microsoft Azure, AWS Cloud and Non-Cloud platforms with Microsoft Technology stack. Currently, I am working as Tech Manager and designated as Associate Manager at Pitney Bowes and managing & leading global mailing products called Tier3 & DLA.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **ASSOCIATE MANAGER - IT** PITNEY BOWES, INC. FEB 2020 - CURRENT



- Leading and managing Tier3 and DLA product operations and automations for global markets.
- Playing a vital role in leading and architecting PBots Self Service portal for automating operational activities.
  - Additionally leading and managing T3Online product development in agile methodologies.
- Playing important role in handling application & server specific vulnerability. Successfully improved Rapid 7 security score from 10+ to 1+.
- Took the charge of managing on premise to AWS migration (completed APAC & EAME regions).
- Currently managing & leading a team of 9 engineers (direct report) and responsible for their KRA, annual goals and performance appraisals.

## **ASSISTANT MANAGER - IT FLEX**



#### JUN 2015 - FEB 2020

- Delivered 3 major releases and more than 50+ sprints successfully on production over a span of 4.5 years.
- Successfully led automated order processing (EDI) worth revenue of ~10 million dollars.
- Managed major release (FY 2018-19) & achieved more than ~110 million-dollar ROI.
- Played scrum master role and managed a team of 6 people (direct report) and driven projects in AGILE methodology using Azure DevOps and was responsible for their KRA, annual goals and performance appraisals.

#### **SKILLS**

# .NET .NET MVC C# Core VB.NET Web API SQL Windows Server Services WCF Web HTML5/ Bootstrap Services CSS3 2-3-4 jQuery Angular Angular TypeScript JS 11-13

| — TOOLS        |          |                       |                 |
|----------------|----------|-----------------------|-----------------|
| 10023          |          |                       |                 |
| TFS            | GitLab   | Jira                  | Azure<br>DevOps |
| Service<br>Now | Remedy   | Pager<br>Duty         | Jenkins         |
| MS<br>Projects | MS Visio | Wireframe<br>Sketcher | Lucid<br>Charts |
| Checkmarx      |          |                       |                 |

#### **CLOUD PLATFORMS**

Azure AWS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (LEAD) L&T INFOTECH

**LT1** 

#### MAY 2014 - JUN 2015

- Involved in collecting requirements for Elevator business and led & designed electronic service dashboard for Otis Elevator customers using ASP.NET, VB.NET and SQL Server 2012, HTML 5, jQuery, bootstrap, CSS3.
- Documented requirement provided by end customers and designed wireframes, functional specs to finalize UI design and system requirement specifications.
- Driven Performance tuning and UAT testing with stakeholders
- Led a team of 12 people. (10 Developers & 2 Testers)

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER HEXAWARE TECHNOLOGIES DEC 2010 - MAY 2014

+i

- Successfully provided production support for AMPS products for the client EY.
- Successfully automated functional/core processes to support critical business requirements of Identity and Access Management domain.
- Designed application code to support end user requirement/business requirement using ASP.NET, C#, SQL Server 2010, jQuery, CSS.
- Assisted in the research, analysis, problems, and coordination of department staff.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering - I.T.

Diploma - I.T.

Pune University

MSBTE, Mumbai

JULY 2010

JUNE 2007

65.13 %

70.17 %

S. S. C.

Pune Vidyapeeth

**JUNE 2004** 

72.80 %

#### PROJECT 1

# TIER3, DLA, T3ONLINE, AWS CLOUD MIGRATION & VULNERABILITY ASSESSMENT PITNEY BOWES, INC.



#### **2020 - CURRENT**

- Responsible for leading and managing Tier3 and DLA product operations and automations for global markets.
- Responsible for implementing ITIL processes for smooth operations.
- Responsible for leading and architecting PBots Self Service portal for automating operational activities.
- Responsible for leading and managing T3Online product development in agile methodologies.
- Responsible for handling application & server specific vulnerability. (Internal and external)
- Managing On Prem to AWS migration which includes estimation, planning, forecasting, and reporting. (Completed APAC & EAME regions)
- Currently managing & leading a team of 9 people (direct report) and responsible for their KRA, annual goals and performance appraisals.

| TECHNOLOGIES  |  |  |  |
|---|--|--|--|
| ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, Web API, SQL Server 2019, Windows Services, Web Services, WCF, Bootstrap 4.0, Angular 4, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3  |  |  |  |
| MANAGERIAL SKILLS   |  |  |  |
| Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, OKRs, SWOT Analysis, Conflict Management, Risk Assessment, Reporting, Strategic Talent Review (Quarterly) with Director and India HR Head.                     |  |  |  |
| FAMILIAR  |  |  |  |
| MS Projects, MS Visio, Jira, TFS, GitLab, Remedy, Dynatrace, PagerDuty, Checkmarx, Jenkins, Ansible, Terraforms, CI-CD, AWS - EC2, Fargate, Container Services, S3 Bucket, Backups, Vaults, CloudWatch, MGN |  |  |  |

#### PROJECT 2

## COMMAND CENTER FLEX



#### 2015 - 2020

- Played agile scrum master role and responsible for solution architect and delivery of the product by leveraging Azure DevOps & CI/CD pipeline.
- Involved in requirement gathering to collect Supply Chain Management business.

Service, Cloud Endure, Lambda Function, Athena, SMS Service, VPC, Subnets, Security Policies

- Delivered 3 major releases and more than 50+ sprints successfully on production over a span of 4.5 years.
- Successfully led automated order processing (EDI) worth revenue of ~10 million dollars.
- Managed major release (FY 2018-19) & achieved more than ~110 million-dollar ROI.
- Developed applications in .NET stack and on Azure platform.
- Played scrum master role and managed a team of 6 people (direct report) and driven projects in AGILE methodology using Azure DevOps and was responsible for their KRA, annual goals and appraisals.

| TECHNOLOGIES  |
|---|
| ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, SQL Server 2019, Bootstrap 4.0, Angular 13, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3   |
| MANAGERIAL SKILLS   |
| Scrum Master, Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, OKRs, SWOT Analysis, Conflict Management, Risk Assessment, Reporting             |
| FAMILIAR  |
| TFS, Azure DevOps, CI-CD, Checkmarx, MS Visio, ServiceNow, Azure - Web Roles, Worker Roles, Web Apps, Azure Functions, Blob, Queues, Tables |

#### PROJECT 3

#### ESERVICE 2.0 L&T Infotech 2014 - 2015



- Involved in requirement gathering to collect/understand Elevator business.
- Documented new requirements provided by end customers and designing draft sketches to finalize UI design for the end customer.
- Designed and maintained application code to support end user requirements.
- Assisted with the technical and functional knowledge of the team during the development and/or maintenance of the software product.
- Effectively handled client calls/issues irrespective of geographic Locations.
- Managed & Led team of 12 people for redesign project.

| TECHNOLOGIES  |  |  |
|---|--|--|
| ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, VB.NET, SQL Server 2012, Bootstrap 2.0, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3       |  |  |
| MANAGERIAL SKILLS   |  |  |
| Scrum Master, Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, Risk Assessment, Reporting |  |  |
| FAMILIAR  |  |  |
| TFS, MS Visio, Wireframes, Lucid  |  |  |

#### **PROJECT 4**

## AMPS (Account Management & Provisioning System) Hexaware Technologies



#### 2010 - 2014

- Successfully implemented interface programs to interact with other platforms and enhance overall functionality of an application.
- Successfully automated core functionality of an application to support business critical aspects.
- Designed SQL scripts to automated workflow which reduced overall cost of resolution and SLA agreed.
- Resolved end user queries/issues in Application at L3/L4 level within defined SLAs.

|  | TECHNOLOGIES |  |  |
|--|--------------|--|--|
| ASP.NET, C#.NET, SQL Server 2012                       |              |  |  |
|  | FAMILIAR     |  |  |
| TFS, Remedy, ERT, ORT, ITIL Processes, Outage handling |              |  |  |

#### **AWARDS**

|  | AWAINDS        |   |                       |
|--|----------------|---|-----------------------|
|  | DECEMBER 2021  | Ace Award   | Pitney Bowes, Inc.    |
|  | <b>~ ~ ~</b>   | Leading and effectively managing Tier3 AWS migration and innovating automation tools.   |                       |
|  | MARCH 2021     | Star Award  | Pitney Bowes, Inc.    |
|  | 2021           | Leading and effectively managing Tier3 and DLA product operations & team and taking smooth hand over of knowledge transition from vendor. |                       |
|  | FEBRUARY 2018  | Gateway – The leaders League  | flex                  |
|  | <b>,</b>       | Leadership Training Program (6 months program)  |                       |
|  | OCTOBER 2017   | Titanium Award  | flex                  |
|  | <b>**</b>      | Designed a self-service web portal and automated all production cases for quicker response. Reduced overall MTR.                          |                       |
|  | SEPTEMBER 2016 | Platinum Award  | flex                  |
|  |                | Designed SQL Deployment Tool for automatic SQL deployments.   |                       |
|  | AUGUST 2014    | Spot Award  | L&T Infotech          |
|  | 7              | For quick understanding of OTIS elevators business and designing outstanding functional requirement specifications.                       |                       |
|  | SEPTEMBER 2012 | Ace Award   | Hexaware Technologies |
|  | 2012           | For effectively handling AMPS production support applications and clients.  |                       |
|  |                |   |                       |